<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://github.com/pages/Fair-Squares/website/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://github.com/pages/Fair-Squares/website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2024-01-19T20:08:13+00:00</updated><id>https://github.com/pages/Fair-Squares/website/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Fair Squares website</title><subtitle>Homepage of Fair Squares</subtitle><author><name>Fair Squares</name></author><entry><title type="html">Invitation to test FS</title><link href="https://github.com/pages/Fair-Squares/website/2024/01/19/invitation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Invitation to test FS" /><published>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://github.com/pages/Fair-Squares/website/2024/01/19/invitation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://github.com/pages/Fair-Squares/website/2024/01/19/invitation.html">&lt;h2&gt; Invitation for Housing Europe partners who want to  co-develop social innovations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1&gt; What is Fair Squares &lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair Squares is committed to let the number of affordable rental houses grow, motivated by the unfair lack of adequate housing. This urgent societal problem we face impacts a huge number of people, also in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The financing costs and also the profits of rental housing can be quite high resulting in rental housing being too expensive. We started in 2021 with the question if organizational technology such as blockchain could help solve one of the main reasons behind the lack of affordable housing. Our hypothesis is that the combination of the further concentration of meanings privatizing social housing structures and rising construction costs are the main reasons for the growth of rental prices and so more housing costs are overburdened in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FS housing operating and financing system is designed and built via public, open source software to enable crowd-capital as a social instrument. The intention is to organize and finance housing more effectively, with less friction, administration and more transparency to achieve lower, more affordable rental prices of houses.&lt;br /&gt;
Instead of a normal landlord or developer putting up all the money, social impact investors within the Fair Squares community will fund projects in exchange for fractional ownership generating a low-risk return that is comparable with other risk-off assets like bonds. Initially, Fair Square will focus on crowdfunding the purchase of residential real estate and in later stages may progress to development or sustainable renovation projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Project status&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of the Web3 foundation Grant Program and several (housing) experts we started to develop the first rough version of the main processes we envisioned. We recently delivered the core of the FS digital coordination framework to connect citizens (testers) who need housing, real estate sellers, social investors, builders, housing corporations,  other real estate professionals, and public policymakers. The guiding principles of the Fair Squares society are affordability, equitability, and transparency in the creation, sale, and renting of residential rental real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fair Squares MVP shows that a reduction of rental costs by at least 15% is possible, compared to the free market by changing the capital structure. Obviously there is a lot of work ahead of us between solving the problem with software and connecting with and embedding into real world institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Invitation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently we are building bridges and connecting with government bodies including Housing Europe, Municipalities, European Union, Universities, Housing Corporations and other housing experts and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are eager to get in touch with organizations who want to test the FS software and processes and learn, improve and cooperate from there. If you are part of an organization who is open to forming their digital transformation radar together with independent projects, please get in contact with us.  We aim to collaborate in order to innovate and create (partly) alternative, digital cooperative financing structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the longer term the base of the Fair Squares protocol also has to enable new forms of financing of projects in order to make existing social rental houses more sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information you can visit our website, documentation our public software repository or email/call us .&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fair Squares</name></author><summary type="html">Invitation for Housing Europe partners who want to co-develop social innovations</summary></entry></feed>